nextavenue.org 2018-10-01

# Privacy Policy - Next Avenue

Next Avenue is owned and operated by Twin Cities Public Television (“TPT” or “Next Avenue” _)_ in St. Paul, Minnesota. We have created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our commitment to the privacy of any information you may provide to us. This Privacy Policy discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the website [www.nextavenue.org](https://www.nextavenue.org/). We are committed to ensuring the privacy of any identifiable information (such as name, address, e-mail address, and telephone number) you may provide to us. We strongly encourage you to read this policy so that you are comfortable with how we collect information and may share information with others.

### Information We May Gather On Our Websites

**Use of cookies and third-party tools**

Next Avenue uses cookies on its websites – small text files that are stored on your computer – to collect information about your visit, personalize your experience, and “remember” you when you return. Next Avenue uses this information to aid the technical administration of the site and to better understand how the site is functioning for its users.

You may turn off cookies that have been placed on your computer by following the instructions on your browser, but if you block our cookies, it may be more difficult (and maybe even impossible) to use some website services.

Next Avenue uses [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics/), Google Universal Analytics and our web servers to gather information about the users of our website. Our web servers and analytics tools will create log files which contain some or all of the following information:

  * The Internet Protocol Address (IP Address) of the computer accessing our website
  * The date, time, location, and length of each visit from each IP Address
  * Certain technical information such as browser being used
  * The path taken through our website and actions taken throughout a session
  * Clicks to links on our site that lead to other sites
  * A record of files downloaded and/or the amount of time spent viewing any video or audio files
  * Any errors encountered
  * Other metrics provided by services such as: Google Analytics and Google Universal Analytics

Next Avenue utilizes [DoubleClick for Publishers (DFP)](http://www.google.com/doubleclick/) and [AdSense](https://www.google.com/adsense/start/) by Google for managing, displaying, and reporting performance of advertisements on nextavenue.org. A cookie may be dropped on your browser when an ad is viewed or clicked. Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior website visits.

DoubleClick and AdSense will collect and report some or all of the following per advertising unit:

  * Impressions
  * Clicks
  * Geo-location of impressions and clicks
  * Certain technical information such as the browser being used
  * Other metrics provided by services such as DoubleClick and AdSense

If you want to opt-out of Google services, [please view this site for more information](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

Except in the event that you violate the [Terms of Use Agreement](https://www.nextavenue.org/terms-of-use), Next Avenue and our third-party vendors acting on our behalf to help deliver the services and operate the Site, will not willfully disclose your personal information to any non-affiliated third party, other than as noted in the _Partnership with other PBS Stations_ section described below. However, this Privacy Policy does not apply to any information or content, including any personally identifiable information that you may provide in any public forums contained on this site, including, but not limited to comments, forums, message boards, reviews, recommendations, ratings, chat rooms. **Next Avenue** will not be responsible or liable for any personally identifiable information you many choose to submit to such public forums.   TPT/Next Avenue does not knowingly collect or store any personal information from any child under the age of 13.

### Information You Give Us

We will not collect personally identifiable information from you, other than what you supply to us on a voluntary basis. However, in order to participate in some activities, you might be asked to provide personally identifiable information. For example, this could be in connection with such things as:

  * Requests from you which require our direct response
  * Subscription registration for sites or services which require subscription (such as email newsletters, though services like [MailChimp](http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/))
  * Contest registration
  * Purchases of merchandise
  * Gathering your comments and feedback
  * Content submissions and suggestions
  * Participation in community postings, bulletin boards or “chat rooms”
  * Participation in surveys

#### Credit Card Information

Your credit card information is considered completely confidential. We seek full compliance with the Data Security Standard as prescribed by the Payment Card Industry when credit card information is provided by phone or mail correspondence. All online transactions take place only on secure servers, and electronic communication of credit card information is sent only in a secured or encrypted format. You must be 18 years of age to engage in money-related transactions on TPT’s website and when utilizing a credit card to make a contribution.

#### Partnership with Other PBS Stations and Next Avenue Affiliates

Next Avenue works in cooperation with PBS stations in communities across America and other organizations that provide information to visitors to Next Avenue that is relevant to a user’s local community. When you register on our site, or sign-up to receive an E-Newsletter or other products or services where you voluntarily give us personal information such as your name, email address, etc., we will share that information with your local PBS station and/or affiliate so that they may communicate with you about other services and information you may be interested in. Because these organizations are non-profit organizations, they may also ask you to support the good work they do in your community.

#### You Should Also Know

Websites operated by Next Avenue may contain links to other sites. Next Avenue is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other websites. Websites operated by Next Avenue may include comment sections, ratings, chat rooms, forums, message boards and/or other interactive elements and public areas where users can post information. Please remember that any information or content that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information in these areas. Next Avenue is not responsible or liable for any personally identifiable or any other information or content presented in such areas by users.  By using websites operated by Next Avenue, you signify your agreement to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to these terms and conditions, please do not use the site. We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this policy at any time. Please check [**nextavenue.org**](http://www.tpt.org/) periodically for any changes. Your continued use of [**nextavenue.org**](http://www.tpt.org/) or any of our other websites following the posting of any changes to these terms shall mean that you have accepted those changes.  TPT/Next Avenue complies with all laws and regulations as applicable to this website, as well as the certification requirements of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting. We also meet the accountability standards for the charitable sector as outlined by the Minnesota Charities Review Council.

Next Avenue supports the Consumer Reports WebWatch guidelines to promote credible information practices on the Web. ([Click here](http://www.consumerwebwatch.org/) for more information on Consumer Reports WebWatch.)

#### Your California Privacy Rights

If you are a California resident, beginning on January 1, 2005, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 may entitle you to receive additional information from us regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes and your right to opt-out of such disclosure. Please direct all such requests to us at the email and/or regular mail address provided below under Contact Us. If you do not want your name and contact information to be shared with any company or organization, you may notify us at any time by writing to us at the email and/or regular mail addresses designated below.

#### Effective Date

This policy was last updated on May 12, 2015.

#### Contact Us

If you have questions regarding this policy, please send an email to [info@nextavenue.org](mailto:info@nextavenue.org) or send mail to Next Avenue, Twin Cities Public Television, 172 E. 4th St., St. Paul, MN 55101.
